<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title>Vocab Story Time</title>
  <link>https://vocabstorytime.com</link>
  <description>Your Podcast Description</description>
  <language>en-us</language>
  <copyright>© 2024 Christopher Lopes</copyright>
  <image>
  <url>https://vocabstorytime.com/VocabStoryTimeLogo.jpg</url>
      <title>Vocab Story Time</title>
  </image>

  <item>
    <title>Definitions: intractable, emollient, obdurate and obsequious</title>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024</pubDate>
    <link>https://vocabstorytime.com/#current-episode</link>
    <enclosure url="https://vocabstorytime.z5.web.core.windows.net/Vocab - Definitions - intractable, emollient, obdurate, obsequious.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="1118592" />
    <description>
Intractable: impossible to deal with or solve; difficult to control or influence.

Emollient: having the power to soften or soothe; calming or relaxing. (noun) a substance that softens or soothes the skin.

Obdurate: stubbornly refusing to change one's mind or course of action; inflexible.

Obsequious: excessively attentive or flattering, in a way that is intended to please someone.
    </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>First Story: intractable, emollient, obdurate and obsequious</title>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024</pubDate>
    <link>https://vocabstorytime.com/#current-episode</link>
    <enclosure url="https://vocabstorytime.z5.web.core.windows.net/Vocab - Story - intractable, emollient, obdurate, obsequious.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="3278592" />
    <description>
In the heart of Silicon Valley, amidst the sleek tech giants and relentless innovation, resided Professor Alistair Hawthorne, a man known for his intractable brilliance and equally intractable personality. He was a genius, his mind a labyrinth of complex algorithms and groundbreaking theories, but his demeanor was as cold and unyielding as the steel beams that framed his laboratory.

One fateful day, a young intern named Emily, fresh out of college and brimming with youthful enthusiasm, was assigned to assist Professor Hawthorne. Emily, armed with an unwavering optimism and an eagerness to learn, approached the professor with trepidation. Professor Hawthorne, however, met her with an obdurate silence, his gaze fixed on the holographic display flickering before him.

Undeterred, Emily persisted. She spent weeks patiently observing the professor, meticulously documenting his research, and offering her insights whenever possible. Slowly, ever so slowly, she began to chip away at his gruff exterior. Her genuine curiosity and unwavering dedication proved to be the emollient needed to soften the professor's hardened edges.

One evening, as they delved into a particularly intricate problem, a breakthrough emerged. Professor Hawthorne, for the first time, acknowledged Emily's contribution, a flicker of warmth replacing the usual stoicism in his eyes. From that moment on, a grudging respect blossomed between them. The once-obsequious intern became a valued collaborator, her fresh perspective challenging the professor's established notions and pushing him to new heights of creativity.

Professor Hawthorne, once a solitary figure shrouded in an impenetrable fortress of his own making, found himself drawn to Emily's genuine nature. He began to share his passion for science, his voice no longer a monotone drone but filled with animated fervor. In turn, Emily learned from the professor's vast knowledge and unwavering dedication, her own talents flourishing under his tutelage.

Their unique partnership, forged from an unlikely combination of brilliance and perseverance, became a testament to the power of human connection, proving that even the most intractable minds can be softened by the right touch.
    </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Second Story: intractable, emollient, obdurate and obsequious</title>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024</pubDate>
    <link>https://vocabstorytime.com/#current-episode</link>
    <enclosure url="https://vocabstorytime.z5.web.core.windows.net/Vocab - Second Story - intractable, emollient, obdurate, obsequious.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="3477312" />
    <description>
Harold regarded the situation with a grimace. Mildred, his normally emollient wife, had morphed into an intractable force of nature. The kitchen, usually a haven of domestic tranquility, resembled a warzone. Flour dusted the air like a ghostly snowfall, and a rogue egg yolk oozed across the counter like a spilled sunrise.
"Harold!"

Mildred's voice, usually as soothing as a summer breeze, now held the icy edge of a blizzard. "This recipe is simply impossible! The dough is like glue, and the instructions are as clear as pea soup!"

Harold, a man who thrived on order, felt a familiar knot of tension tighten in his gut. Mildred's baking endeavors were legendary, for their spectacular failures as much as their occasional successes. He adopted his most placating tone, hoping to soothe the oncoming storm.

"Now now, Mildred," he began, his voice dripping with a touch of obsequiousness he knew she despised. "Perhaps we just need a little more flour..."

Mildred cut him off with a glare that could curdle milk. "Don't you 'now now' me, Harold! This recipe is clearly faulty. The internet comments are full of complaints!"

Harold, ever the pragmatist, knew arguing with Mildred in this state was as futile as trying to herd cats. With a sigh, he donned his metaphorical oven mitts and waded into the culinary chaos.

Over the next hour, Harold transformed into a master baker, gently coaxing the dough into submission with practiced ease. Mildred, initially resistant, watched in grudging admiration as her husband's deft hands tamed the intractable batter.

Finally, a golden brown loaf emerged from the oven, the aroma of success wafting through the kitchen. Mildred, her obdurate demeanor melting faster than butter on a hot pan, beamed.

"Well, I'll be darned," she chuckled, the familiar warmth returning to her voice. "You saved the day, Harold. As always."

Harold, secretly pleased with himself, basked in the afterglow of a culinary triumph. He knew that sometimes, even the most emollient personalities needed a little help, and a touch of quiet competence could go a long way in the kitchen, or any battlefield for that matter. 
    </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Definitions: attenuate, credulity, piquant and sententious</title>
    <pubDate>Tues, 12 Mar 2024</pubDate>
    <link>https://vocabstorytime.com/#current-episode</link>
    <enclosure url="https://vocabstorytime.z5.web.core.windows.net/Vocab - Definitions - Attenuate, Credulity, Piquant and Sententious.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="1058112" />
    <description>
Attenuate: To weaken, lessen, or reduce the intensity or force of something.

Credulity: A tendency to believe readily; gullibility.

Piquant: Pleasingly sharp or stimulating to the taste or mind; having a pleasantly provocative quality.

Sententious: Characterized by the expression of moral or pretentious opinions in a short, concise way; overly moralizing.
     </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>First Story: attenuate, credulity, piquant and sententious</title>
    <pubDate>Tues, 12 Mar 2024</pubDate>
    <link>https://vocabstorytime.com/#current-episode</link>
    <enclosure url="https://vocabstorytime.z5.web.core.windows.net/Vocab - First Story - Attenuate, Credulity, Piquant and Sententious.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="1884096" />
    <description>
Agatha, known for her unwavering credulity, was an easy target for traveling salesmen. One brisk morning, a man with a neatly trimmed beard and a silver tongue arrived at her doorstep. He peddled a device he claimed could "attenuate the negative ions" that were causing Agatha's misfortunes.

Intrigued by the scientific-sounding jargon and her own string of recent bad luck, Agatha listened intently. The salesman's spiel was peppered with piquant anecdotes about people whose lives were miraculously improved by the device. Agatha, desperate for a change, readily bought into his claims, her skepticism attenuated by his smooth talk.

Days turned into weeks, and Agatha religiously used the device, convinced it was working its magic. However, her fortunes remained unchanged. Finally, a neighbor, a man known for his blunt and often sententious remarks, pointed out the obvious - the device was nothing more than a cheap trinket.

Humiliated and frustrated, Agatha confronted the salesman, only to find he had vanished, leaving her with a lighter wallet and a valuable lesson about the dangers of credulity. From that day on, Agatha vowed to approach fantastical claims with a healthy dose of skepticism, never again allowing her credulity to cloud her judgment.
    </description>
  </item>

</channel>
</rss>
